[Music]
Hi and welcome to new busy central
launch edition 2025 release wave 2.
Today we will present you value chain
automation with titan charge and one
part of sustainability module. My name
is Alexander Toto. I product manager and
today I have my colleague with me.
>> Yes, my name is Jacob Bang and I am also
a product manager working with
Alexander.
>> Thank you. So let's look what is about.
If you remember when we started two
years ago if I'm not wrong with
sustainability features we had
sustainability journal, general journal
and sustainability ledger entries.
Actually we didn't have a general
journal. We added it later at the same
time as we added purchase invoices but
all of them produce sustainability
ledger entries. We use them only for
emission for reporting in all three
scopes but for impact for officially for
compliance reasons. But then we
previously uh wave we added new
functionality as a value chain
automation in scope in your scope t as a
carbon footprint only. So what did we
enable? We enabled um to use purchase
invoice not only for sustainability
ledger entry but to create
sustainability value entries plus we
enable transfer order, assembly order,
production order and in this release we
enable projects as well. But what else?
One of small missing parts was maybe
problematic um especially on a purchase
site. We didn't have earlier item charge
assignment. So if you had a transport,
we couldn't handle this as a item charge
in a purchase process. So now in this
release, we enable item charge as well.
So when you look in the business value
this is something what we can look as a
now finally have end to end uh scope of
uh scope three emission tracking. So we
can cover all processes providing this
definitely flexible emission
attribution. So especially to final
reporting related to purchase you can
use different models how you can assign
the same is apply for costs. It will
approve accuracy fully compliance. So
especially if you have upstream or
downstream activities with the transport
some other activities. So you can easily
assign all these emissions into your
purchase process and not only purchase
all your processes. So how does it it
work? I already mentioned it works only
as a carbon footprint. So that means
with a carbon 2 equivalent carbon
dioxide equivalent only. So if you're
using other gas emissions system will
automatically calculate them based on
emissions fees to carbon equivalent
where it will check where it check in uh
posting emissions will possibly own in a
now in a purchase documents when type is
item charge for others we already
covered earlier with resources items and
other models are already configured
already existing. So now we added item
charge and when you have item charge for
both cost expenses and uh for gas
emissions you can assign the same model.
So there is no difference when you
assign the same way it works for uh
financial amounts it will work for
emissions as well. So you can use
equally by amount by weight or volume
all types are covered absolutely the
same. So what do you need to do? You
just need to enable in a sustainability
setup or procurement tab. You need to
enable uh item charge and you need to
enable uh item trackings in emissions.
So once you complete it, you can use. So
now my colleague will show you how it
works in a practice.
>> Yeah. So we've already enabled the um
parameters that Alexander just
mentioned. So let's go to item charge.
And here we'll use freight as the
default.
and we'll put in a account number
and a value.
So, let's go to purchasing
purchase invoice
and we'll create a new one.
Choose our old friends from Fabricam.
We'll make an invoice number.
And for item, we're going to choose item
charge.
Go through it again.
And we need
one quantity. So here we see that the
line amount excluding tax is a,000.
Similar to the emissions that we've saw
from earlier.
Now we'll go to line and related
information
and item charge assignment.
We'll look at the receipt lines here and
we'll just pick up a couple for
comparison.
And now we can go to the suggest item
charts assignment. Now, as Alexander
mentioned, you can switch between
whether you want to do it by amount,
weight, volume equally. Let's try
amount. Take a look at that. Here you'll
see that the CO2 equivalent is assigned
uh with amount. If we want to change
that by equally,
you'll have
the amount uh assigned equally between
the three line items. And of course,
this again this will work in the same
way for weight or for volume. So that's
how you track item charges.
>> Okay. Thank you, Jacob. Before
we close this session, I would just like
to remind you we have important general
resources related to Business Central.
You can have these, you can find these
six links. Please use them to be updated
with all news about Business Central.
And then do not forget to subscribe on
weekly news announcement on our LinkedIn
channel. And the last but not the least,
use our YouTube channel akamsbc YouTube
not only to watch this video other
videos for sustainabilities because
there are a lot of sustainability
features in this release but not only
for sustainability for other features in
this edition previous edition. So
probably we have hundreds of different
videos you can learn about busy central.
Thank you for watching this video.